# Sulin Liu

Sulinl@princeton.edu

Princeton University, NJ 08544

□ +1 (609)-865-7835

github.com/liusulin

### **Research Interests**

My research focuses on developing deep-learning-enabled probabilistic inference and generative modeling, as well as using them to guide exploration and discovery of knowledge in science and engineering. Previously, I have worked on federated/distributed optimization and multi-task learning.

### **Education**

2017-2023	Ph.D. in Machine Learning, Electrical and Computer Engineering, <b>Princeton University</b>
(exp.)	- Advisors : Ryan P. Adams (CS), Peter J. Ramadge (ECE)
2011-2015	B.Eng. in Electrical Engineering, National University of Singapore
	- Minor in Mathematics. Thesis advisor : Cheong Loong Fah
	- Thesis : 3D Scene Reconstruction for Indoor Environment Based on Multiview Homographies
2014	Exchange student, Georgia Institute of Technology
	- 9 students selected university wide

# **Work Experiences**

2021	Research Intern, <b>Meta Research</b>	Mentors : Ben Letham, Eytan Bakshy
May-Aug.	- Developed sparse Bayes optimization for interpretable/	
	paper, collaborated with product team and successfully	deployed the methods in products
2015-17	Research Engineer, Nanyang Technological University	, <b>Singapore</b> Advisor : Sinno Jialin Pan
	- Conducted research in distributed/federated optimization	on, multi-task learning

### **Honors and Awards**

2022	Princeton ECE Travel Grant Award
2022	NeurIPS Top Reviewer Award, 8%
2020	Azure Cloud Computing Proposal Award, \$10,000
2019	NeurIPS Top Reviewer Award, 50%
2018	Anthony Ephremides Fellowship -awarded to the top first year Ph.D. student in the information science track
2017	Princeton University Fellowship in Natural Sciences and Engineering -tuition, fees, stipends
2017	KDD Conference Travel Award
2014	IEEE Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society
2014	Faculty of Engineering Annual Book Prize -awarded to student with the best performance in wireless communications
2013	ST Electronics Book Prize -awarded to the top sophomore in Electrical Engineering
2011-15	Singapore Ministry of Education Undergraduate Scholarship -tuition, fees, stipends

### **Publications**

#### Conference papers

- Sulin Liu\* (equal contr.), Qing Feng\*, David Eriksson\*, Benjamin Letham, Eytan Bakshy
  Sparse Bayesian Optimization, to appear in *International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS)*, 2023. Paper.
- Sulin Liu, Xingyuan Sun, Peter J. Ramadge, Ryan P. Adams
   Task-Agnostic Amortized Inference of Gaussian Process Hyperparameters, in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020. Paper. Code. Slides. Video.
- 2020 Hossein Valavi, **Sulin Liu**, Peter J. Ramadge
  Revisiting the Landscape of Matrix Factorization, in *International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS)*, 2020. **Oral presentation**. Paper.
- Mengchen Zhao, Bo An, Yaodong Yu, Sulin Liu, Sinno Jialin Pan
   Data Poisoning Attacks on Multi-Task Relationship Learning, in AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2018. Paper.
- Sulin Liu, Sinno Jialin Pan, Qirong Ho
   Distributed Multi-task Relationship Learning, in Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2017. Paper. Video.
- 2017 Yaodong Yu\*, **Sulin Liu**\*(equal contr.), Sinno Jialin Pan

  Communication-Efficient Distributed Primal-Dual Algorithm for Saddle Point Problems, in *Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI)*, 2017. Paper.
- Sulin Liu, Sinno Jialin Pan
   Adaptive Group Sparse Multi-task Learning via Trace Lasso, in *International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2017. Oral presentation. Paper.

#### Workshop papers

- Sulin Liu\*(equal contr.), Qing Feng\*, David Eriksson\*, Benjamin Letham, Eytan Bakshy Sparse Bayesian Optimization, in *NeurIPS Workshop on Gaussian Processes, Spatiotemporal Modeling, and Decision-making Systems*, 2022. Contributed talk, top 5 selected. Video.
- Athindran Ramesh Kumar\*, **Sulin Liu**\*(equal contr., random order), Jaime F. Fisac, Ryan P. Adams, Peter J. Ramadge

  ProBF: Probabilistic Safety Certificates with Barrier Functions, in *NeurIPS "Safe and Robust Control of Uncertain Systems" Workshop*, 2021
- Sulin Liu, Xingyuan Sun, Peter J. Ramadge, Ryan P. Adams
   Task-Agnostic Amortized Inference of Gaussian Process Hyperparameters, in 7th ICML Workshop on Automated Machine Learning, 2020. Spotlight talk.

#### **Preprints**

Athindran Ramesh Kumar\*, **Sulin Liu**\*(equal contr., random order), Jaime F. Fisac, Ryan P. Adams, Peter J. Ramadge
ProBF: Probabilistic Safety Certificates with Barrier Functions, *Preprint*, 2021. Paper. Code.

### **Presentations**

### Invited and contributed oral presentations

2022	Marginalization Networks for Discrete Generative Modeling NSF Institute for Data-Driven Dynamical Design Meeting, 2022.
2022	Sparse Bayesian Optimization Contributed Talk at NeurIPS Workshop on Gaussian Processes, Spatiotemporal Modeling, and Decision-making Systems, 2022.
2020	Task-Agnostic Amortized Inference of Gaussian Process Hyperparameters Spotlight Talk at 7th ICML Workshop on Automated Machine Learning, 2020.
2017	Adaptive Group Sparse Multi-task Learning via Trace Lasso International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2017.

### **Selected poster presentations**

2020	Task-Agnostic Amortized Inference of Gaussian Process Hyperparameters
	Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.
2017	Distributed Multi-task Relationship Learning Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2017.
2017	Adaptive Group Sparse Multi-task Learning via Trace Lasso International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2017.

### **Professional Services**

### **Conference Reviewing**

2018-	Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
2019-	International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)
2020-	Asian Conference on Machine Learning (ACML)
2019-2022	International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)
2021	ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD)
2021	SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM)
2020-2021	AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)

## Journal Reviewing

2021-	IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)
2020	Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR)

### **Workshop Reviewing**

2022	AI for Accelerated Materials Design Workshop, NeurIPS 2022
2022	AI for Science : Progress and Promises Workshop, NeurIPS 2022

### **Graduate Coursework**

- -ML: Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition, Theoretical Machine Learning, Theoretical Deep Learning
- **Stats** : Statistical Theory and Methods, High-Dimensional Probability, Statistical Optimization and Reinforcement Learning
- **Optimization** : Linear and Nonlinear Optimization, Optimization for Machine Learning, Large-Scale Optimization
- Control: Safety-Critical Robotic Systems

# **Teaching Experiences**

### **Princeton University**

2021-2022	Co-instructor for SML 310 Research Projects in Data Science, in Fall 2021 & Spring 2022.
	- Undergraduate project-based course on solving real-world problems with machine learning.  Teaching weekly precepts, mentoring students in their research projects, grading.
2020	Teaching assistant for COS 424 Fundamentals of Machine Learning, in Fall 2020
	- Graduate and undergraduate course on machine learning for large, complex data sets, covering fundamental methods of ML. Teaching precepts, grading, providing feedback to final projects.
2020	Teaching assistant for COS 302 Mathematics for Machine Learning, in Spring 2020
	- Undergraduate course covering mathematics topics (linear algebra, probability, optimization) used in machine learning. Teaching precepts, helping prepare homeworks and exams.
2019	Teaching assistant for SML 201 Introduction to Data Science, in Spring 2019.
	- Undergraduate course covering basic methods and programming of statistics and machine learning. Teaching precepts, programming help-sessions.
2018-2019	Teaching assistant for ELE 535 Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition, in Fall 2018 & Fall 2019 (head TA).
	- Graduate course covering fundamentals of machine learning, with a focus on theory. Teaching

### National University of Singapore

2014-2015

Lab tutor for CS 1010E Programming Methodology, in Fall 2014 & Spring 2015.

- Undergraduate course covering introductory fundamental concepts of programming. Teaching lab sessions, grading.

# **Programming Skills**

- Proficient: Python (PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas), MATLAB, LATEX, Git, Slurm, Bash/Zsh

precepts, helping prepare homeworks and exams, grading.

- Familiar : TensorFlow, C/C++, Java, Parameter Server, HTML/CSS, VHDL

# **Open Source Projects**

#### **Creator and Co-creator:**

- AHGP : https://github.com/PrincetonLIPS/AHGP
- $\hbox{- ProBF}: https://github.com/athindran/ProBF$

### **Developer and Contributor:**

- BoTorch : https://github.com/pytorch/botorch
- Ax : https://github.com/facebook/Ax

### References

#### Ryan P. Adams

**Professor of Computer Science** Princeton University Princeton, NJ, USA



### Peter J. Ramadge

Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering Princeton University Princeton, NJ, USA

ramadge@princeton.edu

### Eytan Bakshy

Research Director of Adaptive Experimentation Team Meta Research Menlo Park, CA, USA



ebakshy@meta.com

#### Sinno Jialin Pan

Professor of Computer Science and Engineering Nanyang Technological University Singapore, Singapore

sinnopan@ntu.edu.sg